<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>jekyller.github.io/jasper/</title>
   
   <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
   <description>Mostly a series of why like thats</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Airpods Pro Not For Me</title>
	  <link>/blog//airpods-pro-not-for-me</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2021-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//airpods-pro-not-for-me</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wxlai90/blog/main/assets/images/uploaded/my_airpods_pro.jpg" style="max-width: 720px" />
<span style="font-size: 12px">My AirPods Pro</span></p>

<p>So I got my AirPods Pro back in Sept 2021. There was an online store sale by Courts, and I snapped them up for just $264.00. Which was kinda a steal.</p>

<p>There were a few hiccups though.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The warranty coverage has started in July, 2 months earlier than my actual purchase date.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There was a blue hairline plastic thread embedded deep into the charging case.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>When I noticed the blue thread, I was worried that it could be a counterfeit. But Courts did have a good enough reputation. With the two issues I faced, I decided it was worth a trip down to the Apple Store in Orchard.</p>

<p>When I was there, the staff told me there was nothing he can do for the warranty, and I had to call a separate hotline - which I did and got it sorted out on the same day.</p>

<p>As for the blue thread, he brought it to the service engineer whom used a pair of tweezers to pull them out. Or so he claimed. I didn’t check thoroughly but on the following day, I actually saw the blue thread again. I believe what happened was the thread got lodged in the hinge and nobody noticed it. Knowing what they would do (tweezer it), I decided to just yank it out myself. I tugged hard on it and heard a snap sound. Pretty sure part of the thread is still lodged inside the bottom part of the case (but whatever).</p>

<h2 id="i-dont-like-it">I don’t like it</h2>

<p>Apart from the poor out-of-box experience.
I realize the silicon tips hurt my ears. Unlike my 1st gen airpods, which I can listen to all day and still don’t feel any discomfort.</p>

<p>The spatial audio is a gimmick that I don’t really like either.</p>

<p>The only good feature is the ANC, but even then there are much better ANC earbuds.</p>

<p>The case’s battery drains at a constant rate even when I don’t use them at all. Which is kinda weird.</p>

<p>Overall, I don’t like the Airpods pro for their poor fit to my ears. And since Airpods 3rd Gen just launched, perhaps I will get a set for myself this Christmas.</p>

<p><img src="https://store.storeimages.cdn-apple.com/8756/as-images.apple.com/is/MME73?wid=2000&amp;hei=2000&amp;fmt=jpeg&amp;qlt=95&amp;.v=1632861342000" alt="AirPods 3rd Gen" style="max-width: 720px" />
<span style="font-size: 12px">AirPods 3rd Gen</span></p>

<h2 id="no-introspective">No introspective</h2>

<p>I decided to skip my weekly intro for this week since I am halfway through my re-service. And will simply do one intro for the entire ICT call-up period instead.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
